Jeremy Wagerik

Old Bridge, NJ

Jeremy.Wagerik@gmail.com | 718-541-4933

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-wagerik-7bb13992/

GitHub: https://github.com/Jwag2128

SUMMARY

Driven data analyst and data visualization specialist. Highly experienced manager with extensive experience across multiple facets of business operations. Adept at working independently as well as collaborating with teams. Highly effective at breaking down concepts to be understood by diverse audiences. Excels at finding and presenting solutions to complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools: Excel(VBA, Vlookup, Pivot Tables), Python, R, SQL, Tableau, HTML, JavaScript, CSS **Libraries/Databases:** Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-Learn, Plotly, Leaflet, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Bootstrap, GeoJSON, AWS

PROJECTS

Loan Predictions | https://github.com/Jwag2128/Loan Predictions

- **Summary:** Use current loan status and financial features to predict whether future applicants are likely to default.
- Tools: Python, Machine Learning, SQL, Tableau

Bike Sharing Usage | https://github.com/Jwag2128/bikesharing

- **Summary:** Create visualizations for a proposal to open a Bike Sharing company.
- Tools: Python, Tableau

Earthquake Mapping | https://github.com/Jwag2128/Mapping_Earthquakes

- **Summary:** Display Earthquake occurrences from a 7 day period.
- Tools: HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Belly Button Bacteria | https://github.com/Jwag2128/Belly_Button_Dashboard

- Summary: Interactive dashboard to display bacteria samples and volunteer information.
- Tools: HTML. JavaScript. CSS

UFO Sightings | https://github.com/Jwag2128/UFOs

- **Summary:** House UFO sighting data in a web application.
- Tools: HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Stock Analysis | https://github.com/Jwag2128/stock-analysis

- Summary: Make recommendations on stocks best suited for investments.
- Tools: Excel, VBA

EXPERIENCE

General Manager, Staples Connect | Jersey City, New Jersey | 7/2020 – Present

- Grew overall store sales by 10%, \$350,000.
- Increased store Operating Profit by ~\$75,000 and beat budget by 40%
- Invested in building internally resulting in 5 promotions to Supervisor or higher.
- Partnered with community leaders and small businesses.

Field Loss Prevention Manager, Staples, Inc. | New York/New Jersey | 7/2007 – 7/2020

- Identified and implemented solution for preventable price markdowns resulting in ~\$300,000 savings
- Developed training program to onboard new Keyholders implemented throughout company.
- Achieved Top 5 performer status for 10 years with Internal Investigation closure rate.
- Elected as a Directors Award Recipient for Excellent Performance and Partnership.

Loss Prevention Operational Auditor, Staples, Inc. | New York/New Jersey | 2/2006 – 7/2007

- Improved Internal Audit scores by 600 bps.
- Implemented audit tracking system.
- Led a Regional training class to highlight operational opportunities.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization, Rutgers University, 11/2022 Interview and Interrogation Techniques, Wicklander-Zulawski and Associates Electronics Engineering Technology, DeVry Institute of Technology, North Brunswick, Nj